Hello Namaskar Jai Hind Vande Mataram.  You are watching
Jio News and we have brought for you
quick big news of selected importance from the country, world and your state and city.  But
before that, if you have not subscribed to our channel, then
subscribe to the channel and turn on the bell notification
and like and
share this video as much as possible.  Today's question for you before looking at the big news.
Which
planet is located closest to the Sun?  Option A Venus, Option
B Earth, Option C Mercury and Option D
Mars.  Answer this question by commenting and tell us
which state and city's news do you
want to see more?  Tell us by commenting
so that we can show more news of your state or city.
Let us now see today's quick
big news.
Food items and personal care
products will become expensive.
Raw material cost pressure on companies.  Packaging
material became costlier by 56%.  In the coming days, there may be
demand for essential consumer products of daily use.
According to the report of Systematic Research,
companies are constantly under inflationary pressure due to rising prices of raw materials.
So that they can increase the prices of their products.  Let us
tell you that it has also been said in the report
that
companies of different categories have increased the
prices of their products by an average of 3 to
7% in the last one to two months.  The main
reason for this is that the cost of raw material
basket of companies has been increased by an average of about 10%.
Karnataka CM Siddharth Ramaiah
resigns.  He said that he did whatever the high command said.
Minister said DK Shivakumar will be the next
Chief Minister.  Karnataka
Chief Minister Siddharth Ramaiah has
resigned.  He said in a press conference in Bengaluru
that I had already said that
I will resign whenever the high command asks me to.  The
high command said so and today I
resigned.  He said that he has
submitted his resignation to the secretary of Governor Thawar Chand Gehlot.  Gehlot is currently
out of Bengaluru due to family reasons.  After this, it is
considered certain that Deputy CM DK Shiva Kumar will become the Chief Minister.
This can be announced in the meeting of the legislative party.
Siddartha Ramaiah's removal
is believed to be under the rotational CM formula and
before this Siddartha Ramaiah held a
meeting with the ministers at his home and
informed them about the decision.  During the meeting, DK
Shiva Kumar touched the feet of Siddha Ramaiah
after which both of them hugged each other.
High level meeting at Rajnath Singh's house regarding NEET exam.
PMO officials including Education Minister Pradhan were also present.  NTA
extended the deadline for fee refund.  A high-level meeting is underway
at the residence of Defence Minister Rajnath Singh on the NEET issue
and
Education Minister Dharmendra Pradhan,
Jyotiraditya Scindia, NTA DG
Abhishek Singh and senior PMO officials
are present in this meeting.  Following the cancellation of the exam, the
National Testing Agency (NTA) has extended the deadline for
submitting bank account details for fee refunds
till June 22 at 11:50 pm.  The
previous deadline was May 27.
Plus versions of WhatsApp, Facebook and Instagram will be available.
This will cost money.  The
story will not be removed even after 24 hours.  You will be
able to create separate lists of favorite people.  Social
media company Meta has introduced
new subscription plans for Instagram, Facebook and WhatsApp.
Under this, plus versions of apps are being
rolled out and
users taking this plan will get special tools and
customization options.  The move
is part of Meta's strategy to create new revenue streams beyond advertising and the new
Plus plans will not replace the company's existing Met Verified
plans.  Meta has just announced the
global rollout of these new Plus subscription plans.
But the company has not announced its launch date in India.   The
earnings of 36 regional political parties declined by 52% in 2024-25.  21 parties
spent more than they earned.  ADR report.   The
total income of 36 regional political parties declined by 51.57% in 2024-25
and the total income of these parties
stood at Rs 10192.94 crore.  Whereas in 2023-24 it was Rs 2463.17
crore.  That means there has been a
decrease of ₹1270.23 crore in one year.  According to the ADR report released in New Delhi,
21 out of 36
regional parties have spent more than their declared income.  The
total expenditure of these parties has been
₹1433.07
crore.  Which was about Rs
240.12
crore more than the total income and this was about 20% more expenditure than the income.   If you have any
income other than salary, then fill ITR 2.
Online filing for assessment year 2026-27
begins.  Returns can be filed till 31st July.  The
Income Tax Department has made
live the Excel utility of ITR Form 2 for assessment year 2026-27 and financial year 2025-26.
And now taxpayers can prepare
their tax accounts by downloading it from the department's portal.
Earlier, the department had
started the facility of ITR One and ITR 4 on May 17.  Now you
can fill your tax data on Excel sheet even without internet.
After filling the form completely, a JSON file will be
created which you will have to upload on the Income Tax portal.
If you are filing returns for the first time,
you will have to register on the portal using your PAN and Aadhaar.
Mukesh Ambani did not take salary for the sixth consecutive year.
Earning ₹3996 crore from dividend.  Mukesh Ambani, the world's 22nd richest person and
Asia's richest businessman, has
not taken any salary from his oil to telecom and retail giant Reliance Industries Ltd for the sixth consecutive year.
According to the annual report released by the company,
Mukesh Ambani's
salary, allowances and retirement benefits will remain
completely unchanged in the financial year 2025-26 (FY 2026) and at present his
main source of income is the dividend received from the company.
Mukesh
Ambani is the 22nd richest person in the world.
After Iran, Trump threatened Oman and said that I will
not tolerate anyone's control over me and
I do not care about the elections.
After Iran, US President Donald Trump has now threatened Oman.  He
said that the Strait of Hormuz is an international sea
route and no single country can occupy it.
All the ships of the world will have the
freedom to pass through here.  Iran is in
talks with Oman to develop a system to collect fees from ships passing through the Strait of Hormuz.
Trump said that we will keep an eye on Horrormoose
but no one will control it.  Iran
wants to control it but that will not happen.
This is international waters and
Oman will have to behave like other countries
or they will blow it up.
Earlier, Trump had said that Iran thought
that he would back out of the talks but now
Tehran has no
other option left except to reach a deal.
Sacrifice of 700 kg Trump buffalo stopped in Bangladesh.  It was auctioned for Eid for ₹3 lakh.
Now sent to National Zoo.
In Bangladesh, the
sacrifice of the white buffalo known as Donald Trump was stopped on Eid.
This buffalo was sold for 3.85 lakh taka i.e.
around ₹3 lakh.  According to news agency
ANI, the buffalo was bought by
Mohammad Suroon, a resident of Rasulpur area of ​​Jinjira, on
May 23 for sacrifice on Eid ul Adha.
Earlier he was living in
Rabia Agro Farm located in Narayanganj near the capital Dhaka.  The
price of this 700 kg buffalo was fixed at 550 taka per kg.
Trump will organize a fight in the White House on his birthday.  The
stage is being set for the competition.
1 lakh people
will watch the match for free.  US President Donald
Trump will turn 80 on June 14, and to mark
the occasion, Ultimate
Fighting Championship (UFC) matches will be held at the White House.
UFC is the world's largest
mixed martial arts (MMA) organization
and in it players from different fighting sports
compete against each other.
UFC chief Dana White said that the
idea of ​​holding the fight in the White House came from
Trump himself.  According to him, for this a
special fighting area is being created in the South Lawn of the White House.
Where more than 4000
people can sit.
Indore city Qazi said that cow should be
declared a national heritage.  The worshippers raised their hands in
support.  Appeal to drain rain water into the ground.
On the occasion of Eid, a
beautiful picture of communal harmony and Ganga-Jamuni culture
emerged from Indore, the cleanest city of the country.  Here,
just before the prayers at the Idgah located in Sadar Bazaar, city Qazi Dr.
Ishrat Ali gave the message of harmony to the society.
He has openly
advocated considering cow as a national heritage.
Which was supported by thousands of Namazis present there by
raising their hands.  After this,
Eid prayers were offered peacefully.
Supreme Court's rebuke ineffective.
Sand mafia active in Chambal.  Tractor trolleys passing in front of police stations and SAF check
posts.  It
is reported that
despite the strong displeasure and strict instructions of the Supreme Court,
illegal sand mining and transportation
is continuing unabated in the National Chambal, Gharial Sanctuary area.  The sand mafia is so fearless that
they are speeding past police stations and SAF check
posts in broad daylight with tractor trolleys full of sand.
Recently, videos of tractors carrying sand in a convoy have also surfaced from National Highway 44 and Forest Department check
posts.
Who are
openly exposing the security system of Chambal.   The
Supreme Court Collegium
sent five names to the Centre.  Recommendation for appointment of Supreme Court Judge.
Chief Justices of four High Courts and
a senior woman lawyer.  The Supreme Court
Collegium has
recommended five names
to the Central Government for appointment as judges in the Supreme Court and this includes four
Chief Justices of High Courts and one senior woman.  The
college has sent the names of
Chief Justice Seal Nagu of Punjab and Haryana High Court,
Chief Justice Shri Chandrashekhar of Bombay High Court,
Chief Justice Sanjeev Sachdeva of Madhya Pradesh High Court
, Chief Justice Arun Palli of Jammu and Kashmir and Ladakh High Court and
senior
advocate V Mohana.
After the Galwan tension, the path for India-China trade will open again.
After 7 years,
Indian traders will go to Taklak Court from Lipulekh Pass.  Let us
inform you that the Lipulekh trade route, which was
closed after the 2020 Galwan conflict on the India-China border, is
now going to reopen.  A
list of 300 traders from Pithoragarh in Uttarakhand has been sent to the Ministry of External Affairs.
Traders will be able to reach Taklakot market in Tibet through visa-free passport trade pass.  The
special thing is that this
time, for the first time, due to the road reaching the border, the
goods will be transported by vehicles instead of horses and mules.
CBI arrests retired judge's mother-in-law in Twisha case.  Will
present in the court after medical checkup.
Visuals of the incident site were recorded using a 3D camera.  Let us tell you
that
CBI has arrested retired judge Giribala Singh in the death case of Bhopal actress Tisha Sharma.
CBI officials have reached the
MNIT campus, Maulana Azad National Institute
of Technology, with Tisha's mother-in-law, Giribala Singh.  Here a medical
board will be called and his checkup will be done.
After medical checkup, Giribala will be
produced in the CBI court.  CBI has
set up a camp office in the Maniit campus itself.
Relief from heat in 15 states including Rajasthan and MP.  Rain alert for the next three days.
Sriganganagar in Rajasthan is the hottest place in the country.
More than 15 states of the country are going to get
relief from heat.  There may be rain in Rajasthan,
Madhya Pradesh, Bihar, UP for the next three
days and an
orange alert has been issued in 22 districts of Bihar.   The
wind speed here can reach 60 km/h.
In Rajasthan, there is an
alert of storm and rain in 11 districts including Jaipur.
Jaisalmer, Phalodi, Sriganganagar, Bikaner
were the worst affected by the heat wave and
Sriganganagar in Rajasthan was the
hottest city in the country.  The temperature here crossed 48° Celsius and
reached 48.2° Celsius.
Drone surveillance of mosques in Delhi and UP on Bakrid, flag march in Bengal.
Protest by Muslims in five states,
declare cow as national animal.  The
festival of Bakrid was celebrated across the country and
Muslim devotees reached Eidgahs to offer prayers.
PM Narendra Modi and
President Draupadi Murmu also
wished the countrymen on Eid.   The
Jannati Darwaza was opened at the shrine of Khwaja Moinuddin Chishti in Ajmer, Rajasthan.
Police and
Rapid Action Force are conducting flag marches in UP, Bengal and Delhi.
Mosques and Eidgahs are being monitored through drones
and
this time the worshippers reached the mosques and Eidgahs of Uttarakhand and Chandigarh with
posters.  On which it was
written declare cow as national animal.
Members of the Haj Welfare Society of Rajasthan have also demanded that the cow be declared the national animal.  The
Muslim community of Telangana and West Bengal is also
demanding that the cow be declared the national animal.
Kakoli Ghosh alleges Kalyan Banerjee
abused me.  Wrote a letter to the Lok Sabha Speaker.   He had
resigned from all the posts of TMC a day ago.  TMC MP from Barasat, Bengal,
Kakoli Ghosh has
written a letter to Lok Sabha Speaker Om Birla and in it
she has lodged a complaint against TMC MP Kalyan Banerjee for
misbehaving and abusing her inside the Parliament.
Kakoli Ghosh wrote
that I want your permission to file a formal complaint.
Kalyan Banerjee has
verbally insulted me several times inside the Lok Sabha.
This behavior of his has been against many other
women MPs.
I want him to be punished for this.
Thought of the day: If you can't make money while you sleep,
you'll have to work until you die.   Do let
us know how you liked this video in the comment section.  If you
liked the video then please
like and share the video and to watch such interesting
videos subscribe to our channel Jio
News and press the bell icon
and do check
our playlist and
community tab to watch our old and latest videos.  So see you
in the next video.
Thank you for now.